58 Glentham Road London, SW13 9JJ +44 7860 582 208 ⊠ naomifaithpyburn@gmail.com

NAOMI PYBURN

I am a self-motivated communicator with 5+ years' experience in impact storytelling, writing, and editing. I value thinking at a systems level and using creative approaches to tackle the problems society faces, most urgently, the climate and ecological crisis.

Experience

Apr 2019 – Present Newsletter & Mass Email Coordinator, Extinction Rebellion (XR).

Grew and led a team of 50 volunteers within XR's Media & Messaging team. Grew email list from 20k to 350k global subscribers and developed consistent tone of voice. Worked on cross-channel messaging strategy for mass participation actions, facilitated group meetings, and collaborated with an international team. Supported adoption of self-organising governance systems. Helped develop systems to hold conflict within the movement.

Aug – Dec

Writer, Extreme Hotel, Dominican Republic.

2018

Wrote 100 articles for adventure eco hotel and sustainable aquaponic farm. Assisted with marketing and general strategy in a period of significant transition.

Jan 2017 – Jun 2018 Impact Women Researcher, Ogunté CIC.

Produced profiles on women social entrepreneurs. Identified and reached out to established individuals. Researched, wrote, and edited interviews for online publica-

tion. Wrote series of blog posts collating findings.

Jan – Jul

Chief Writer, Sugarwise.

2017

Managed the written content and operations at an early-stage food certification startup. Liaised with clients and customers to ensure satisfaction. Designed graphics for use in marketing materials. Recruited and trained new team members. Organised and attended events.

Aug 2016 –

Deputy Editor, Wet Zebra Media.

Feb 2017

Sole paid employee in a digital publishing startup, requiring fast learning and impeccable organisation. Responsibilities include selecting and editing manuscripts, communicating with authors, launching social media campaigns, organising and hosting events, managing web content, training interns, and writing news articles.

Jul 2012 – Jul

Founder & Editor-in-Chief, INK Student Magazine.

2013

Co-founded and edited online student publication 'INK', which won several categories at national Shine Media Awards. Led a team of over 50 students and members of staff. First experience of Adobe InDesign. Gained proficiency at editing and proof-reading, effective people management, and adapting quickly to new challenges.

Education

2013 - 2016

English BA (Hons), University of Cambridge, 2.i.

Developed rigorous work ethic, juggling workload with extra-curricular pursuits. Learned the value of precise and concise writing.